<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>machine-learning on John Ingle - Software Development</title>
    <link>https://johnathaningle.github.io/categories/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in machine-learning on John Ingle - Software Development</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://johnathaningle.github.io/categories/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Essence of Mean Squared Error</title>
      <link>https://johnathaningle.github.io/posts/essence-of-mean-squared-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnathaningle.github.io/posts/essence-of-mean-squared-error/</guid>
      <description>What you need to know: The smaller the means squared error, the closer you are to finding the line of best fit.
Depending on your data, it may be impossible to get a very small value for the mean squared error. Advantage: It is useful if we have unexpected values that we should care about. Abnormally high or low values should be paid attention to.
Disadvantage: If we make a single very bad prediction, the squaring will make the error even worse and it may skew the metric towards overestimating the model’s badness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coursera Machine Learning Introduction Quiz</title>
      <link>https://johnathaningle.github.io/posts/coursera-machine-learning-introduction-quiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnathaningle.github.io/posts/coursera-machine-learning-introduction-quiz/</guid>
      <description>Question 1 A computer program is said to learn from experience E with respect to some task T and some performance measure P if its performance on T, as measured by P, improves with experience E. Suppose we feed a learning algorithm a lot of historical weather data, and have it learn to predict weather. In this setting, what is E?
Answer The process of the algorithm examining a large amount of historical weather data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supervised vs Unsupervised Learning</title>
      <link>https://johnathaningle.github.io/posts/supervised-vs-unsupervised-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnathaningle.github.io/posts/supervised-vs-unsupervised-learning/</guid>
      <description>Supervised Learning In supervised learning, we are given a data set and already know what our correct output should look like, having the idea that there is a relationship between the input and the output.
Supervised learning problems are categorized into &amp;ldquo;regression&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;classification&amp;rdquo; problems. In a regression problem, we are trying to predict results within a continuous output, meaning that we are trying to map input variables to some continuous function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Derivatives in Python</title>
      <link>https://johnathaningle.github.io/posts/simple-derivatives-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnathaningle.github.io/posts/simple-derivatives-in-python/</guid>
      <description>A rocket has been programmed to follow the path $y = x^2$ in space (from left to right along the curve, as seen in the margin figure), but an emergency has arisen and the crew must return to their base, which is located at coordinates (3, 5). At what point on the path $y = x^2$ should the captain turn off the engines so that the ship will coast along a path tangent to the curve to return to the base?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
